Have you seen any such health insurance in
which the premium does not increase with age? Have
you seen such a health
insurance plan in which maternity cover of up
to Rs.1.25 lakh is available in a waiting period of just 12 months?
So
keeping women in mind, ICICI Prudential
Life Insurance and RDA Re-Insurance
Group of America, which is a re-insurance
company and is one of the biggest companies in the world,
both of them together have come up with an
excellent plan named
iProveWis. Watch the full video. If you like the video, then do
like, share and subscribe to my YouTube2 Triple FS
where you will
find more than 300 videos which will
help you in your financial planning related to insurance. Thank you. Till now you will
see that in all the women-centric
insurance products, either
pregnancy or child care cover is
excluded; they are
not included. Secondly, the payment is
only for the treatment.
Suppose you have purchased a policy of Rs. 10 lakh. If you are
admitted in the hospital and you are billed for Rs. 1 lakh, then
you get only Rs. 1 lakh and the
rest  You do not get ₹1 lakh. Thirdly, there is
no guarantee of premium. In
all the products made till now,
your premiums keep increasing with age.
But in this
new product launched by ICICI Bank, there
is a comprehensive cover, all the women specific
elements are being covered. Plus, if
any disease is diagnosed, suppose
cancer is diagnosed, then suppose you had
purchased a policy of 20 lakhs, then you will get 20 lakhs in
one go. It has nothing to do
with the hospital treatment bill.
Thirdly, suppose you are a 30 year old woman
and have purchased a policy, whether your age becomes
35, 40 or 50, your
premium will not increase. There is a guarantee of premium in this.
So these are all the features which are
very good. Features have been given in this policy.
Now let us see that
three things will be covered in it, one is
critical illness will be covered, one
surgery will be covered, one maternity
benefit will be covered.
Whenever we talk about critical illness, then
vital care cover will be provided whenever any  If you hear about Vital Care Cover
or purchase a policy, it
means they are talking about critical illness.
When someone talks about surgical care cover, it
means they are talking about the benefit of surgery
and in maternity care cover,
maternity is talked about. Now first of all let us
understand the feature of critical illness i.e.
vital care cover.
In this critical illness, you will be covered with 11 women
specific critical illnesses in
which there will be five major critical illnesses and
six minor critical illnesses. First let us
understand the five major critical illnesses and later we will
understand the minor ones. In major, these five
critical illnesses are covered in which seven types
of cancers including breast
cancer, uterine cancer, uterus cancer, ovary cancer, these types
of cancers will be covered.
First heart attack will be covered in it,
stroke will be covered in it, systemic
lupus will be covered in it and arthritis which is
also called arthritis will also be covered in it. For
example, if you see the seven cancers that I told you about under Vital Care, let me
tell you one thing, in India breast cancer is very common.
Every 4 minutes, someone is getting diagnosed with a female condition. You must have heard that
a leading TV actress, Hina Khan,
also recently faced a similar problem, and the
treatment costs 10 to 25 lakh rupees.
In today's times, health insurance or
medical expenses
increase at a 14% inflation rate, meaning that
these treatments become more expensive every year at 14%. So,
if you have insurance,
you can get treatment and recover from these diseases. The
big thing is that
you can recover. Another thing is
cervical cancer. You must have seen that it is a big
news that every 8 minutes someone dies. Every
8 minutes, a person
suffering from cervical cancer dies.
Secondly, heart attack will also be covered in this and
stroke-related problems will also be covered. The
average cost of these today
ranges from 2 to 12 lakh rupees. The
risk of heart attack, especially in women, has
doubled in the last 20 years.
You will also have to consider this.  Systemic lupus is a disease
that can also cause kidney failure. It
affects the kidneys greatly.
Arthritis, which we call arthritis in Hindi, will
also be covered under this policy.
In today's times, the cost of this type of illness ranges from ₹2 lakh to ₹1 lakh. So,
these are five major diseases which will
come under major illness under Vital Care. Six minor
illnesses will be covered. Let's see which ones will be in the minor category. The
first is early stage
breast or cervical cancer. The
second is fracture of spine and hip.
All these will also be covered. If seen in this, the
cost ranges from ₹1 lakh to ₹1 lakh.
60 million Indians, that is, about
6 crore Indian women, are suffering from this type of
problem, out of
which 80%
are women. In this, you have loss of bladder control
or your pelvic muscles have become weak
or you have a thyroid disorder. These will also be
covered as minor illnesses in this policy. The
treatment of these illnesses will be covered.  The
expense as of today is coming between Rs 500 to Rs 5 lakh.
If we talk about major illness, for example, a woman has
purchased a policy in which she has taken vital care of Rs 20 lakh, that is, she has
taken the benefit of critical illness and if she gets
any of the five major illnesses,
then the entire Rs 20 lakh will be paid as a lump
sum and the policy will
stop there. These are the features of vital care,
they will stop there. If a minor illness is
covered, then
you will get a certain portion of vital care up to Rs 10 or Rs 50 as per that disease. Whatever is left, let us say you got the
claim on Rs 10, whatever is left will continue.
So till now we have seen critical
illness which is also known as vital care cover.
Now let us see
which surgeries will be covered in this surgical care cover for
women.  Nine
surgeries related to cancer will be covered, in which there will be five
major surgeries and four minor surgeries.
What will be included in the major surgeries? One is
breast reconstructive surgery, the second
surgery is skin grafting due to major burns.
If there is a major burn, then
skin grafting will also be
covered in it. The remaining
three surgeries below are related to your reproductive
organs. They will be counted in the five major surgeries. The
four minor surgeries are
organ surgeries done for post-cancer treatment, which will be covered in it.
Now suppose a woman has
purchased a policy in which she has
taken a surgical care cover of Rs 10 lakh, then if she has a
claim in five major surgeries and she is
also diagnosed, then Rs 10 lakh will be
paid together and the
rest of the policy benefits like vital care etc. will
continue in it and
your premium related to surgery will be reduced,
next year your premium will be reduced by
that much
and in minor surgeries, you will get
surgical care cover up to 40%.  Look, there is a cover of Rs 10 lakh, but Rs
4 lakh will be paid to you.
Your
policy will continue with the remaining amount and
your premium will also be reduced by the amount reduced.
Now let us understand a scenario. Suppose
you have purchased the policy
and in this, the cover for surgical care comes before the claim for vital care. If a claim is made, then
what will happen? The cover for surgical care will be
paid and
your premium related to it will be reduced
and the rest of your policy will
continue. Now let us look at scenario number two,
where first a 100% claim comes for vital
care i.e. critical illness and
after that a claim for surgery comes, then what will happen?
You will get the full 100% cover for critical illness. The
policy will be
closed but the benefits related to your surgery will continue for one year. So, for
now, we have understood the critical illness cover, the
surgery cover. Now let us
look at the third one, maternity.  Benefit Maternity Care
Cover: This will not be inbuilt, it is an optional
benefit, you can add it. There are
two options in this, the first one is Critical and
Surgery, which will be called Health Care, and if you
take all three options, Critical Surgery and
Maternity, then
this package is known as Health Care Plus in this company.
Now let's see Maternity Care Cover, which is
optional, you can add it by paying an additional premium.
22 problems will be covered here, out of which nine
will be related to pregnancy and 13 will be
related to illness of the newborn baby.
You can see here which nine complications in pregnancy will be
covered. As of today, the
treatment of these complications costs you Rs. 2 to ₹
lakh. For illness of the newborn baby,
you will see four mentioned here.
I will explain the remaining 13 in the benefit illustration further,
which are the other things that are covered.
Its expense as of today  It ranges
between ₹50,000 and ₹2 lakh.
Now, let's assume a woman has
purchased this policy, including a
maternity benefit of
₹1 lakh. If there are pregnancy
complications or a newborn baby-
related illness, the entire ₹1
lakh will be paid to her, and all
other policy benefits and features will continue.
Now, we have also understood maternity cover. Let's
understand it with an example:
if you have purchased a health insurance policy, say,
medically, for
30 years. Suppose you purchased the policy, the
premium for health insurance
increases every year. Secondly, maternity
benefits are not available in most plans. If they are
available in some plans, the
waiting period is three to four years. The
waiting period for this is only 365 days.
Secondly, you can also take a larger cover here, you
can also take a cover of ₹5 lakh or 10 lakh.
There, in most of the plans, it is hardly 1 lakh or 2
lakh. Thirdly, the
premium keeps increasing there. Here, your
premium will remain constant. The
policy you purchased at the age of 30, the
same premium will be coming to you at the age of 55.
Now let us understand the premium guarantee
through out the policy term. Plus, let us
understand it by an example. A 30-year-old woman has
purchased this policy in which vital
care is of 10 lakhs, that is, for critical illness 10
lakhs, she has taken the option of 5 lakhs for surgical
care, then her
premium is coming for 10 years. If
we take regular premium payment, then it is
9786 in which GST is not included.
If you keep the term for 20 years, then for 12752 and by
paying a premium of 860, you
can avail the benefit of 10 to 5 lakhs for 30 years. Now,
another great feature has been given in this plan,
which is called premium subbutting, that is,
you get the benefit of one premium, that is
You purchase the policy,
even if you do not pay the premium in any one year,
your policy will continue. Suppose
you had to pay the premium for 10 years, you
paid the premium for 9 years and you did
not select this option, then
your premium will not be automatically paid for 10 years. If we
sum up the premium payment, suppose
you have taken 10 years, then you have to pay the premium for only 9 years. If you
want, you
can take a break in between, otherwise
your premium will be waived off in the last year anyway.
Now let us understand the
insurance cover that you will take, vital
care, you can take between Rs 10 lakh to Rs 50 lakh.
Surgical care, which you will take for vital
care, will be available for Rs 50. If you have
taken vital care for Rs 20 lakh, then you will be
able to take surgical care for a maximum of Rs 10 lakh. But if you have taken vital care for Rs 50 lakh,
then you will be able to take surgical care for Rs 25 lakh.
Maternity care, which will be your base cover, will be
at Rs 25 lakh, that is, if you have
taken vital care for Rs 20 lakh.  So if its percentage
becomes Rs 5 lakh then you will get a maternity benefit of Rs 5 lakh
but if you have taken Rs 50 lakh
then your maternity cover will also increase
so the maternity benefit which is available in a very small amount in health insurance,
here you will be able to take maternity cover of a bigger amount as well,
so I had told in the beginning that vital
care and surgical care are known as health care
package, vital care,
surgical care and maternity care all three are
known as health care plus,
now talking about its eligibility criteria,
here your entry age can be purchased by a
person between 21 years to 55 years,
you will be able to take maternity only between 21 to 37 years,
policy term you can
take a policy term from 8 years to 30 years,
maximum till the age of 75 this policy will
mature, maternity will mature at the age of 45,
you can make premium payment every
year, you can make it for 10 years, 15
years  You can avail this cover during premium payment.
Talking about medical underwriting guidelines,
suppose your age is 35 years and you
take cover up to Rs 30 lakh, then there is
no need to get any medical test done. If
your age is between 36 to 50, then
you can take cover up to Rs 15 lakh as non-medical.
If your age is up to 50 years and you
take insurance cover of 10 times your income, then there is
no need to provide income proof. If your age is
between 51 to 55 and
you take cover five times your annual income, then you will
not need to provide income proof. Now if we talk about the
underwriting guidelines of this policy, then to
take this plan, it
is mandatory to have passed at least 12th class plus your income should be Rs 1 lakh.
But if you
are a housewife or a student, then
you can take cover up to Rs 20 lakh even without providing income proof. If you take
cover of more than Rs 20 lakh, then income proof
is mandatory. NRIs can also avail this policy.  You
can purchase cover up to 20 lakhs. NRIs
can also purchase it.
So here, all the women who are
between 21 to 55 years of age can purchase this policy.
Those who already have a medical policy
running can also purchase it.
Suppose you have purchased this policy of 20 lakhs, 20
lakhs plus 10 lakhs plus 5 lakhs.
Suppose your health insurance
policy is also running for ₹ lakhs. You have cancer, you got
admitted in the hospital and the
bill came for 8 lakhs. Then you claim 8 lakhs from the medical policy
and you will get 20 lakhs from here also. You will get
benefits from both.
And if it is a male person, suppose it is a husband, then
he can
purchase this policy for his wife and daughter also. A proposal can be made.
So now let us understand the benefit illustration of this product of ICICI Pencil. Well,
I have already explained all these features to you, in which there is
a woman
whose  He is 30 years old and is taking a vital care cover of Rs 20 lakh, a
surgical care cover of Rs 10 lakh
and a maternity cover of Rs 5 lakh.
So, here in vital care
you have 11 illnesses, nine surgeries and 22 are
covered for your maternity benefit. Here
I have taken a policy term of 10 years and a
premium payment term of 10 years.
Here you will get the benefit in the premium even
if you do not pay the premium for one year,
as I
told you as an example, here your premium will be Rs
31,316. ​​GST will be added to it and the
premium will come to Rs 36,000. Now we have already seen
what all is covered under critical illness.
If a
major critical illness is diagnosed, then you
get the entire money 100% and the policy gets
discontinued. If a minor critical illness
occurs, then there is a fixed certain portion and
you get that along with the rest of the benefits.
They continue. We have already seen what all covers will be there in surgical care
and here
if a major
problem is diagnosed then you will get 100% money related to the surgery
and your policy will continue along with the rest of the
benefits and features and
your premium will be reduced by 95% next year. Similarly,
if there is a minor surgery then
you will get money at 40% and after reducing the premium by 95%, the
rest of the benefit covers will start.
Talking about maternity cover, we have
seen all the other things that which
maternity complications are covered here.
There you saw four benefits for child,
you can see the rest of the 13 here
and here you see what happens
and diagnosis of maternity new, then here
you will get 100% money like this one, for
example at the age of 30 and the
premium of 11744 coming for maternity will be
yours from next year.  It will start coming less once you have
taken the maternity benefit. If we
talk about ICC potential here, then till now
around 10 crores have been covered.
By June 2024, the company has a net worth of 3 lakh
crores. This company has a net worth of 3 lakh crores and there is
also claim settlement.
This benefit will come in your policy bond.
Like I told you that a 30 year old woman
and a non-smoker is purchasing the policy
and this is a non-participating non-linked
health plan, that is, she will get tax benefit under section 8D of income tax, in which there is
vital care of 20 lakhs, surgery of 10 lakhs,
maternity of 5 lakhs, which I have already
told you. If you see the premium of vital care here, it
is 000 without GST, that
of surgery is only 2795, that of maternity is 744. A
total
premium of 316 is coming in it without
GST.
Now you will see that when you purchase the policy, the
policy bond that will come to your home,
in that policy bond you will get  First of all, you will
get a customer information sheet. This is mandatory
in all the companies after the new changes on 1 October 2024. Here you will get the
name of the plan, the
name of the category of the plan, the
policy number will also be written.
What type of health plan it is,
that too will be mentioned. How much premium you have to pay,
how much you are covered in surgery,
maternity, all this will be
available to you here at the beginning of the policy. How many
years the premium has to be paid, how long the policy will run,
what are the benefits in this policy, all these will
also be mentioned here. What are the
exclusions, after how much time will pre-assisting diseases be
covered, all those things will be
mentioned here along with the exclusions.
How much waiting period will be there? There
is a waiting period of 90 days in vital care, there is a waiting
period of 90 days in surgery and
you have a waiting period of one year in maternity,
whereas in health insurance there is a
waiting period of about three to four years. Regarding the
claim, how long will the wait be for which service,
you can find out this in this.  You
can also know about the claim form
etc. by clicking on the link. If you want to know more, you can know about it. If
you want to call the customer care, you
can call. You will also get information about the digital claim form.
You can purchase and download the physical claim form from this link.
And if you want to make a complaint etc., then
you will get all the information about where to do it at the beginning of the policy. The
free loan will be valid for 30 days
and when you purchase the policy, then give your correct
information like date of birth, gender, education,
annual income, details of your occupation,
address in which country, your address, pin
code set. You must tell us already if you are
running any insurance, then
definitely give its information. Give all the correct information about your habits like alcohol or
smoking etc., height, weight etc.,
otherwise there can be an impact on the claim. So, as per the
new rule,
you will get the customer sheet and customer information
sheet at the beginning of your policy bundle
and if you like it, then while leaving you will
get more than 2 of my YouTube videos which will give
you term plan saving.  Will help you in
financial planning like retirement, child education, marriage etc.
Thank you so much Jai
Hind